Andre De Coppet Collection, 1566-1936 (bulk 1770-1865 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Coolidge, Calvin (1872-1933), 1919-1930; 3 boxes (2 partial)
  - Correspondence, 1914 April 2-1930 May 15; 2 folders
    - Andrews, Charles A., 1919 May-1920 September 29; portion of 1 folder
      - Andrews, Charles A., 1920 September 24; 1 item (Folder 15)
        TLS from Coolidge's secretary, Henry F. Long, explaining that Coolidge will likely miss Andrews' banquet due to a speaking engagement with the National Republican Committee. 1 p.
      - Andrews, Charles A., 1920 September 29; 1 item (Folder 15)
        TLS from Coolidge's secretary, Henry F. Long, reiterating Coolidge's inability to attend Andrews' banquet. 1 p.
    - Clark, [Edward T.], 1921 April 16; 1 item (Folder 15)
      ALS (initials), Hotel Touraine, Boston. To Clark, his private secretary, directing him to forward the President's [Warren G. Harding] speech on coal and railroads, and prevent Coolidge's own speech to the Veterans of Foreign Wars from being placed in the Record. 1 p.
    - Dana, Richard Henry, 1923 November 15-December 9; 2 folders
      - Dana, Richard Henry, 1923 November 15; 1 item (Folder 15)
        TLS, The White House, Washington. Thanking him for a suggestion to modify the process of selecting Presidential postmasters. 1 p.
      - Dana, Richard Henry, 1923 November 30; 1 item (Folder 15)
        TLS, The White House, Washington. Recalling their conversation about the Civil Service. 1 p.
      - Dana, Richard Henry, 1923 December 9; 1 item (Folder 15)
        TLS from Dana to Coolidge. Praising him for his message to Congress regarding Civil Service. 1 p.
    - Denny, Daniel E, 1919 January 13; 1 item (Folder 15)
      TLS, Boston. Thanking the senator and his colleagues for sending flowers on the occasion of Coolidge's inauguration. 1 p.
    - Greenway, Cornelius, 1922 October 9; 1 item (Folder 15)
      ALS, Vice-President's Chamber, Washington. To Greenway at Tufts College, one sentence on the "aim and duty of a college man." 1 p.
    - Grondahl, Joseph, 1924 April 2; 1 item (Folder 15)
      TLS, The White House, Washington. To the President of the Safety First League, endorsing his efforts to reduce automobile accidents. 1 p. with original envelope.
    - Holt, Hamilton, 1927 February 14; 1 item (Folder 15)
      TLS, The White House, Washington. Sending greetings to the annual meeting of the Florida Historical Society. 1 p.
    - Lowell, Freeman L, 1917 December 18; 1 item (Folder 15)
      ALS, Boston. Enclosing a small check. 1 p. with original envelope.
    - O'Shea, Michael, 1914 April 2; 1 item (Folder 15)
      TLS, Boston. Thanking O'Shea for a leaflet on the protective tariff. 1 p.
    - Peyser, Julius I, 1924 January 23; 1 item (Folder 15)
      TLS, The White House, Washington. Declining an invitation to a banquet of the Order of B'nai B'rith. 1 p.
    - Scott, Walter, 1919 September 17-1923 March; portion of 1 folder
      - Scott, Walter, 1919 September 17; 1 item (Folder 15)
        TLS, Boston. Thanking Scott for his support, expressed in a letter to a Mr. Munro. 1 p.
      - Scott, Walter, 1923 March 31; 1 item (Folder 15)
        TLS, Northampton, Mass. TLS, thanking Scott for books; outlining his traveling schedule with the hopes of meeting. 1 p.
    - Walker, Henry C, 1924 May 9; 1 item
      ALS, The White House, Washington. Saying that if Walker has trouble walking he has all the more time to improve his mind. 1 p.
    - Young, Alton M, 1925 December 3; 1 item (Folder 15)
      TLS, The White House, Washington. Commending the work of the Volunteers of America during the Christmas season. 1 p.
  - Manuscript, circa 1918-1920; 1 item (Folder 15)
    TMS. "The Measure of Progress." Championing the measure of success as the quality of manhood, not the quantity of merchandise. 1 p.
  - Photographs, dates not examined; portions of 2 boxes
    Filed by subject.
    - Coolidge, Calvin, undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 15)
      Signed images of Coolidge in various formats (photograph, reproduction sketch, reproduction photograph -- four in total, one housed in Box 46 (oversize).
    - Coolidge, Grace, undated; 1 item (Folder 15)
      Signed photograph of the President's wife.
    - Cabinet, undated; 1 item (Folder 15)
      Signed photograph of Coolidge and his Cabinet.
- Cornell, Ezekiel (1733-1800), 1776 December 29; 1 item (Folder 16)
  ADS, to the Council of Safety, Philadelphia. A return of prisoners "from Headquarters." 1 p.
- Coxe, Tench (1755-1824), 1808 September 26; 1 item (Folder 17)
  American political economist. ALS to Charles Thompson, former secretary of the Continental Congress, requesting materials for a proposed biography of John Dickinson and reporting the death of friend David Jackson. 3 pp.
- Cranfield, Edward, 1684 November 10; 1 item (Folder 18)
  Served as Governor of New Hampshire. DS, sealed, agreement with Robert Elliot regarding some boards in Cranfield's possession. 1 p.
- Crawford, Samuel Johnson (1835-1913), 1863 June 21; 1 item (Folder 19)
  American general, served as third Governor of Kansas (1865 – 1868). Draft letter, Upton's Hill, Virginia. To an unidentified general, reporting on various military movements including [Joseph] Hooker's plans to attack [Robert E.] Lee. 2 pp. [Affiliation with Crawford based on provenance.]
- Cruger, John (1710-1791), circa 1757-1766; 1 item (Folder 20)
  Served as mayor of New York (1757-1766). DS, with two seals, portion of a larger document forwarding a writ of certiorari. 1 narrow strip.
- Cullimore, Isaac, 1641 October 2; 1 item (Folder 21)
  DS, signed by two others (Samuel Bright, Nick Upsall). Deed of land sold from Bartholmey Passmore of Boston to John Sweet, provided that Sweet finish the house on the property. Recorded 1650 and 1704. 1 p.
- Cushing & White, 1767-1795; 3 boxes (1 partial)
  This series consists of the papers of business partners Samuel White and John Cushing (1743-1822), merchants and privateers during the American Revolution. Cushing & White operated out of Boston and acted as administrative agents and part-owners in multiple vessels that sailed along the North American coast and to the West Indies. John Cushing appears to have been the leader in the partnership as the bulk of papers bear his name. Cushing was a native of Massachusetts, born in Scituate, Plymouth County in 1743 to John and Deborah Barker Cushing. In 1773 he married Olive Wallingford, daughter of Colonel Thomas and Elizabeth Wallingford. He was chosen Colonel, 2nd Plymouth County Regiment in 1776 but resigned the commission in 1779 citing ill health. By that time, he had already started his merchant and privateering partnership with Samuel White. By definition, privateers were privately funded but government sanctioned vessels that preyed on enemy ships. Captured ships were known as "prizes," and the goods and cargo on board were sold to the profit of the owners and crewmembers. Privateers played a significant role in the American Revolutionary War, outnumbering government-owned vessels by more than ten to one and capturing nearly 600 British ships over the course of the war. Cushing & White acted as agents and owners of various ships outfitted for privateering, most prominently from 1777-1780. They experienced both successes and failures but by 1784 seemed to have fallen into serious financial difficulties. A letter dated 1787 to "John Cushing—Supervising partner of the late House of Messrs. Cushing & White" suggests by then the partnership dissolved—either due to bankruptcy or the death of Samuel White. Papers dating from 1784 onward suggest Cushing continued to earn his living as a merchant. The papers in the series are largely focused on the privateering years, and include correspondence, financial records, and official documents often signed by captains and crewmembers. Subject matter is focused on investments, prizes, the sale of captured goods, and the threat of the enemy. Of note is a printed license to arm issued by the Continental Congress and signed by president John Hancock. The papers are arranged alphabetically by name of ship, with miscellaneous material at the end. Known information about the ship is given in the description. Within the ship folders, the papers are arranged chronologically unless otherwise noted.
  - Ship Alexander, 1784 December 20-1785 June 2; portions of 2 boxes
    - Insurance Policy, 1784 December 20; 1 item (Folder 1)
      Insurance policy purchased for Alexander's trip from Portsmouth to the West Indies, issued to John Cushing by the office of Edward Payne. Printed form. 1 leaf.
    - Bill of Sale, 1785 January 1; 1 item (Folder 1)
      Bill of Sale of ship from Alexander Romain to John Cushing. 1 folded leaf.
    - Receipt, 1785 April 23; 1 item (Folder 1)
      Receipt for French custom house duty. Printed form. 1 leaf.
    - Pass, 1785 April 23; 1 item
      Pass from French admiral L. J. M. de Bourbon (oversize). Printed form. 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 1785 April 30; 1 item (Folder 1)
      AL (copy) from John Cushing to authorities in Hispaniola in response to seizure of ship. 1 folded leaf.
    - Receipt, 1785 June 2; 1 item (Folder 1)
      Receipt for anchor. Half leaf.
  - Ship Alliance, 1779 January 5-1783 April 15; 1 folder
    Alliance was a frigate captained by Peter Lander (aka Pierre Landais) in 1779. In 1783, under Captain John Barry, Alliance took part in the last Naval battle of the American Revolution.
    - Contract, 1779 January 5; 1 item (Folder 2)
      James Bragg's (ship's carpenter) obligation for a quarter share of all prizes accrued to be paid to Cushing & White. 1 leaf.
    - Account Statement, 1783 April 15; 1 item (Folder 2)
      Accounting of prize money for the officers & crew. Signed by Captain John Barry. 1 p.
  - Ship Black Queen, 1787 July 19-26; 1 folder
    - Letter, 1787 July 19; 1 item (Folder 3)
      ALS from John Walmsley explaining his tardiness in paying money owed; accompanied letter from Joseph Valentine (below). 1 folded leaf.
    - Letter, 1787 July 20; 1 item (Folder 3)
      ALS from Joseph Valentine regarding failed attempt to collect money from John Walmsley. 1 leaf.
    - Bill, 1787 July 26; 1 item (Folder 3)
      Notarized bill of money owed to John Cushing by John Walmsley for prosecuting claim for the ship Black Queen. 1 leaf.
  - Ship Cabbot, 1777 June-September; 1 folder
    The Cabbot/Cabot was a brig captained by Elisha Hinman in 1776. In 1777 it became the first Continental naval ship taken by the British.
    - Correspondence, 1777 June-September; 1 item (Folder 4)
      On one sheet of paper is a series of correspondences between Cushing, White, and attorneys regarding prize money and wages owed two crew members of the Cabbot who sailed under Hinman. 1 leaf.
  - Ship General Hancock, 1778 February 20-1779 February; 2 folders
    On September 19, 1778, under Captain Ishmael Hardy, the privateer General Hancock successfully defeated the British ship Levant when a shot hit Levant's magazine causing an explosion and the death of most of her crew. Soon after, with the help of American privateer Beaver, General Hancock successfully took Lady Erskine. The file contains documents and correspondence in preparation for and in response to the 3-month cruise during which the above took place. The papers are housed in two folders: Documents and Correspondence.
    - Documents, 1778 June-November; 1 folder
      File contains a collection of official documents drawn up for the June 1778 cruise of General Hancock. Arranged chronologically.
      - Articles of Agreement, 1778 June; 1 item (Folder 5)
        Signed by captain and crew agreeing to a 3-month cruise starting June 28, 1778 against "enemies of the United States of America." 1 large folded leaf.
      - Powers of Attorney, 1778 June; portion of 1 folder (Folder 5)
        Two powers of attorney for various crew members. 1 leaf each.
      - Orders, 1778 June 23; 1 item (Folder 5)
        Cushing & White's signed copy of their orders to Captain Hardy. 1 folded leaf.
      - Warrant for Delivery, 1778 November; 1 item (Folder 5)
        Warrant for delivery requiring Cushing & White to deliver barrels of indigo to Benjamin Tatem, master of captured prize ship Charity. 1 folded leaf.
      - Muster Roll, undated; 1 item (Folder 5)
        List of names of the officers and crew with their stations and shares. 1 folded leaf.
    - Correspondence, 1778 February 20-1779 February; 1 folder
      Correspondence from investors in General Hancock, including Christopher Leffingwell (1734-1810), a prominent Connecticut businessman who funded multiple privateering vessels in support of the Continental Army. Leffingwell also referenced General Hancock in correspondence found in the Minerva file. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
      - Bull, William, 1779 February; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS requesting his share of prize money. 1 folded leaf.
      - Lamb, James, Jr, 1778 June; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS buying share in ship ( General Hancock not mentioned by name but deduced based on date, other correspondence). 1 folded leaf.
      - Lamb, James, Jr, 1778 June 8; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS, received report that ship is slow but pledges to buy a share despite. 1 folded leaf.
      - Leffingwell, Christopher, 1778 February 20; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS offering money to fund ship. 1 leaf.
      - Leffingwell, Christopher, 1778 March 2; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS regarding funding of ship. 1 leaf.
      - Leffingwell, Christopher, 1778 May 5; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS requesting update after receiving news there has been difficulty manning the ship. 1 leaf.
      - Leffingwell, Christopher, 1778 June 3; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS suggesting the name of a potential Prize Master. 1 leaf.
      - Leffingwell, Christopher, 1778 October 28; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS requesting news of ships General Hancock and Minerva. 1 leaf.
      - Leffingwell, Christopher, 1779 February 28; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS settling accounts related to ships General Hancock and Minerva. 1 folded leaf.
      - Lockwood, Ja, 1778 May 28; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS requesting his brother be added to the crew. 1 folded leaf.
      - Lockwood, Ja, 1779 January 24; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS requesting his share from sale of ship. 1 folded leaf.
      - Lockwood, Ja, 1779 February 26; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS requesting his share from sale of ship. 1 leaf.
      - Olmsted, Aaron, 1778 December 4; 1 item (Folder 6)
        ALS requesting his share of money from potential sale of ship. 1 folded leaf.
  - Ship Margarett, 1777 June 26; 1 folder
    Margarett was captured as a prize by the Cushing & White ship Satisfaction in March 1777.
    - Receipt, 1777 June 26; 1 item (Folder 7)
      Receipt for sale of Margarett. 1 leaf.
  - Ship Minerva, 1777-1779; 3 folders
    The ship Minerva was built in 1777 at Old York for Cushing & White. File contains information related to two cruises. The first, a three-month cruise under Captain John Grimes, sailed in June 1778 and resulted in the successful capture of eight British prize ships off the coast of Newfoundland. During the second cruise, in June of 1779, Minerva and two other American privateers were captured by the British and carried to Antigua. Papers housed in three folders: Documents (First Cruise), Documents (Second Cruise), Correspondence.
    - Documents (First Cruise), 1777-1778; 1 folder
      File contains documents related to Minerva's construction and first cruise, sailed June-August 1778. Arranged chronologically.
      - Day Book, 1777 September-November; 1 item (Folder 8)
        Day Book of ship Minerva, kept during its construction at Old York. 20 pages, bound.
      - Bill of Sale, 1778 January 22; 1 item (Folder 8)
        Bill of sale for new ship Minerva, built at Old York. Sold by John Stone to Messrs. Cushing & White. 1 leaf.
      - Invoice, 1778 March 5; 1 item (Folder 8)
        Bill of supplies and services bought of Dr. John Greenleaf for Minerva. 1 leaf.
      - Contracts, 1778 May 24-26; portion of 1 folder (Folder 8)
        Two crewmembers signed obligations to give a quarter share of all potential prizes to Cushing & White. 1 leaf each.
      - Muster Roll, 1778 June; 1 item (Folder 8)
        List of names of crew with their respective shares.1 leaf.
      - Account Statement, 1778 November 14; 1 item (Folder 8)
        List of owners (shareholders) and balances owed each after the sale of prizes taken in the 1778 cruise. 1 large folded leaf.
      - Record Book, 1778; 1 item (Folder 8)
        Records and accounts of the 1778 cruise of Minerva, under Captain John Grimes. Includes weekly inventories of provisions and crew, lists of captured vessels and prizes, and copies of letters and orders given by captain to prizemasters. Among crew members was Robert Cushing, related to owner John Cushing. 60 pages, bound.
    - Documents (Second Cruise), 1779; 1 folder
      File contains documents related to Minerva's second cruise, sailed June 1779. Arranged chronologically.
      - Articles of Agreement, 1779 June; 1 item (Folder 9)
        Signed by captain and crew agreeing to cruise from Boston to West Indies and back. 1 large folded leaf.
      - Ledger, 1779; 1 item (Folder 9)
        Alphabetized records of money awarded crew members after capturing the prize ship Revenge (early June 1779). Cover verso gives brief timeline of ships activities April-June 1779. 24 pages, bound.
    - Correspondence, 1778 May 30-1779 August 24; 1 folder
      Correspondence, largely from investors in Minerva. Prominent are Peter & Isaac Wikoff and Christopher Leffingwell (1734-1810), a Connecticut businessman who funded multiple privateering vessels in support of the Continental Army. Leffingwell also referenced Minerva in correspondence found in the General Hancock file. Arranged alphabetically.
      - Austin, David, 1779 April 22; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS from David Austin requesting an administrative position onboard the Minerva. 1 folded leaf.
      - Austin, Elijah, 1778 November 7; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS requesting settling of accounts and prize money owed. 1 leaf.
      - Blair, Archibald & Robert, 1778 October 15; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS settling account of shares in ship. 1 folded leaf.
      - Broom, John, 1778 June 20; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS suggesting a man to fill the roll of Captain Mariner. 1 leaf.
      - Griffin, Samuel, 1778 May 30; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS requesting news of the ship. 1 folded leaf.
      - Griffin, Samuel, 1778 October 20; 1 item (Folder 10)
        AL (copy) regarding the sale of his shares of Minerva to Messrs. Peter & Isaac Wikoff. Sent with October 26, 1778 letter from Wikoffs. 1 leaf.
      - Grimes, John, 1778 September 17; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS from Captain reporting safe return to Old York after 3-month cruise during which he captured eight prizes. 1 leaf.
      - Leffingwell, Christopher, 1778 October 10; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS requesting his share of prizes taken by Minerva, as well as note regarding General Hancock, another Cushing & White ship in which he invested. 1 folded leaf.
      - Leffingwell, Christopher, 1779 January 1; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS and copy of previous letter regarding fate of ships General Hancock and Minerva, including the possibility of selling both ships to Congress. 1 leaf.
      - Purviance, Sam & Robert, 1778 June 20; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS from Sam and Robert Purviance, shareholders, requesting news of the ship. Included is a copy of a previous letter sent April 23, 1778. 1 folded leaf.
      - Sheaf, Jacob, 1778 June 22; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS requesting payment for rum and sundries purchased for Minerva. 1 leaf.
      - Wikoff, Peter & Isaac, 1778 October 26; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS requesting their portion of prizes be sent in goods, not cash. 1 folded leaf.
      - Wikoff, Peter & Isaac, 1779 January 19; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS. Detailed letter giving suggestions for Minerva's next sailing, as well as a long list of goods requested in lieu of cash. 1 folded leaf.
      - Wikoff, Peter & Isaac, 1779 April 13; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS requesting a variety of textiles as payment. Post script mentions Minerva will next set sail for the West Indies. 1 folded leaf.
      - Wikoff, Peter, 1779 June 22; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS regarding Minerva successfully taking a British ship. Also writes about the cost and availability of goods during the war. 1 folded leaf.
      - Wikoff, Isaac, 1779 July 12; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS discussing family life, conditions in Philadelphia, and the successful capture of various prize ships. 1 folded leaf.
      - Wikoff, Peter & Isaac, 1779 August 17; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS regarding insurance for Minerva, lately arrived at Hispaniola.1 folded leaf.
      - Wikoff, Peter & Isaac, 1779 August 24; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS responding to news Minerva was captured by a Liverpool privateer. 1 leaf.
      - Wooster, Thomas, 1779 May 20; 1 item (Folder 10)
        ALS explaining delay in payment. 1 folded leaf (torn).
  - Ship Neptune, 1784 December 14-1795 March; 1 folder
    - Bill of Lading, 1784 December 14; 1 item (Folder 11)
      Issued by John Cushing to ship's Master John Callahan for voyage from Boston to London. Printed form. Half leaf.
    - Journal, 1795 March; 1 item (Folder 11)
      Unbound journal of a voyage from Portsmouth, NH to Barbados kept by Samuel N. Cushing, mate aboard the Neptune. Mathematical records of location and notes on weather. 1 large folded leaf.
  - Ship Revenge, 1779 October 23; 1 folder
    Revenge was captured as a prize by the Cushing & White ship Minerva in June 1779
    - Orders (copy), 1779 October 23; 1 item (Folder 12)
      Cushing & White's signed copy of their orders to Captain Elisha Turner to sail from Boston to Hispaniola and back (prohibited from privateer cruising). 1 folded leaf.
  - Ship Runfast, 1776 October-1777 February 12; 1 folder
    Runfast was used by Cushing & White as a commercial schooner, not directly involved in privateering.
    - Pay Voucher, 1776 October; 1 item (Folder 13)
      Signed by four crew members agreeing to wages. 1 leaf.
    - Insurance Policy, 1776 December 14; 1 item (Folder 13)
      Insurance policy purchased for Runfast's trip from Virginia to Boston. Printed form. 1 leaf.
    - Orders (copy), 1777 January 13; 1 item (Folder 13)
      Cushing & White's signed copy of their orders to Captain Nehemiah Tomes, to sail from Boston to Baltimore and back. 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 1777 February 3; 1 item (Folder 13)
      ALS from Cumberland Dugan (Baltimore flour merchant), concerned the British ships off the coast of Maryland are preventing Runfast's arrival. 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 1777 February 12; 1 item (Folder 13)
      ALS from Cumberland Dugan confirming the capture of Runfast by the "Kings Ships," bemoaning the war's influence on the markets for various perishable goods. 1 folded leaf.
  - Ship Satisfaction, 1777-1789 April; portions of 2 boxes
    Satisfaction, a sloop, completed at least two cruises under the administration of Cushing & White. The first, under Captain John Stevens, ended somewhere between March and May 1777. The second, under Captain John Wheelwright, took place from June 1777-October 1777. Satisfaction took prizes in both instances. The papers suggest payment of prize money after the second cruise was rather contentious.
    - Ledger, 1777 March; 1 item (Folder 14)
      Ledger containing the division of prizes from captured ships Margarett and Royal George, taken March 1777 under Captain John Stevens. 100 pages, bound.
    - Receipts, 1777 March; portion of 1 folder (Folder 15)